

Social data scientist and demographer with more than 10 years of experience designing, managing, supervising, and analyzing applied and academic social studies. Strong quantitative-qualitative skills and theoretical background. Eager to apply my knowledge and skills to solve social problems and work with interdisciplinary teams. Authorized to work in the U.S.

Skills

- o Data Science: Machine Learning, NLP, Visualization (Dash, Shiny), pySpark, SQL, Databricks.
- Modeling: Proficiency and experience in statistical and demographic techniques (GLM, multilevel models, SNA, SEM, survival analysis, causal inference, Bayesian statistics). Agent-Based Modeling (ABM) and Simulation. See publications on my website.
- **Research**: Designed, analyzed and presented research in academic conferences applied and academic research projects on social inequality, education, public opinion, social psychology, adolescent behaviors, and social networks.
- Survey Research: Experience designing and implementing questionnaires using different modes (in-person, phone, web), sampling and analysis adjustments (weights, missing data). Created R package sampler for practitioners.
- **Project Management**: Led more than 20 research national and international projects, teams of 40 people, and manage an annual budget of US\$400,000.
- **Software**: Statistics: R, Stata, Mplus, HLM, SPSS, SAS, CTM, Stan, INLA. Qualitative software: Nvivo. Data entry and processing: CSPro. Social Network: Ucinet, R-Siena. Agent-based modeling (ABM) and System Dynamics: Anylogic, Netlogo.
- Programming: Python, Java (basic).
- o Languages: English (fluent) and Spanish (native).

Professional Experience

Senior Quantitative Social Scientist

Juntos Inc May 2018—present

Provide user insights through design and analysis of experiments, NLP and machine learning.

Research Associate

Center for Justice and Society Studies, Catholic University of Chile

2016-present

Co-investigator of the project Women Re-entry Study.

Methodology Consultant

Center for Social Studies (DESUC), Catholic University of Chile

August 2010-present

Designed sampling and post-adjustments in nationally representative studies in Chile. Provided methodological guidance (attrition, non-response adjustments).

Research Assistant

University of Wisconsin-Madison

July 2012-August 2018

Participated in four academic research projects. See my website for details.

R Package Developer

Applied Population Laboratory (APL), UW-Madison

2014-2018

Created and maintained the R package acsr to help extract variables and statistics using the America Community Survey and Decennial US Census.

Director

Center for Social Studies (DESUC), Catholic University of Chile

2005-2010

Led projects in areas such social cohesion, political perception and government approval ratings, education, tobacco and substance, crime and delinquency, and organizational studies. I was involved in writing grant proposals, budget estimation, methodological design (theoretical framework, sampling design, instruments), analysis and presentation of results. A key project was the Survey of Social Cohesion in Latin America(ECosociaL) that involved 7 countries: Chile, Argentina, Brazil, Colombia, Guatemala, Mexico and Peru, and 10,000 cases.

Lecturer

Catholic University of Chile

2008-2009

Taught courses on advanced methods for social research, qualitative analysis, and design and implementation of social surveys.

Education

Ph.D. (ABD) in Sociology and Demography University of Wisconsin-Madison, US	2010-present
• Fellow • The Data Incubator, US. Capstone Project: Tracking sent	iment of Congress members' tweets 2017
Master of Arts in Sociology Catholic University, Chile	2009
Bachelor of Arts in Sociology Catholic University, Chile	2004